Hi, I'm Craig.
Hey, I'm Sarah.
And we're going to be your hosts on this exciting journey where you learn to program.
Let me just tell you a little bit about myself.
I have a background in technology.
I have a PhD in education technology.
And what are my real passions has been coding.
I absolutely love it.
And there was nothing more exciting than when my daughter also wanted to get into coding.
So I am in my final year of coding in university and I've absolutely loved it so far.
I can't wait to go and do postgrad in computer science next year and continue my programming journey.
I've really loved every minute of it, and I'm really looking forward to sharing this love with all
of you.
Yes.
So we want to tell you, why should you be learning to program?
Simple fame.
It's all about fame.
Now, I'm not necessarily saying you're going to become famous.
You may well.
And we know there are lots of people that have become famous with the things they've coded, like people
like Mark Zuckerberg, Bill gates and others.
But Fame is an acronym that stands for Fun achievement, Millennial Age, Survival Skills, and earnings.
So let's have a quick look at those.
So fun Coding can be so much fun.
I know most people kind of think coding might be sitting in a dark room typing on your computer, but
really it's the complete opposite.
You.
Firstly, you are creating something new, something exciting.
It almost feels like you are telling a story.
And by tapping your code out on your computer, you are making things happen.
You're creating a game and it's just such an exciting experience, and it's one of the most enjoyable
things that I love to do.
You're going to find out why it's so much fun, but that brings us to our next thing achievement.
Achievement is something that we all like.
And Sarah's going to tell you a little bit of why programming just gives you this incredible sense of
achievement.
So brain challenging.
I can definitely agree with that one.
Programming constantly challenges your brain.
I mean, look at that brain.
You try to find out solutions to problems that might not even exist.
So you spend this time working, trying to figure something out.
But when you get that program working, when you get that answer right, it is the most amazing feeling.
Then secondly, you are making things.
You are You're creating things.
Once you've finished your game, you have this physical thing that you can go and show someone, wow,
look, this is what I did.
And they can go try it out and they can physically see what you have created.
And it's, you know, I just want to break in on, you know, what?
To me, I'd love to be an artist or something or write books.
And often we don't have those skills.
But it's so nice when you've done those things.
You've made that painting.
You can look at it and go, wow and show people it well, whether you can do that or not, that's something
you can do with coding.
You can write this program that stays behind.
It sits in an app store.
It sits on your computer.
It's such an incredible sense of achievement.
Yeah.
So I was going to say it's always there.
It never disappears.
And lastly, it helps you become efficient.
There's so many things that are repetitive in your life.
It might be something you're doing on your computer or that you need to do over and over.
You can use coding to do that for you.
It may be that you need an app to store your makeup items or or balance your books, or whatever it
might be.
Coding allows you to do all of these things for yourself.
You make your own apps, really makes your life a lot more efficient and productive, right?
But that leads us to the M.
It's fun.
That's all exciting, According.
But more than this, you get to these millennial age survival skills.
These are these skills that we need now.
In the past, when you lived in the in the dark ages, in the caves, we needed skills like making fires
and running faster than the saber toothed tiger.
Now we need different skills to survive.
We need skills.
And these are skills that have been identified as critical.
If we want to do well in our modern world.
Skills like being accurate, knowing how to solve problems, being prepared to take risks, a vital
skill in this modern world, being creative, being productive, learning how to work together, and
collaboration.
A really important one.
Persistence.
Not giving up because too many people give up too quickly.
Being curious and then also thinking logically.
And every single one of those millennial age skills is developed in coding.
And so as you learn to code, you learn to become persistent, creative, logical, all of these incredibly
important skills.
So not only do you learn to code and produce code and produce programs, you learn these skills that
will set you in a good place for whatever your career and whatever you're doing in life in the 21st
century.
Entry.
And so that then brings us to the E which is earnings.
Earnings is a critically important one because we all like earnings.
And in terms of earnings the first thing is employment opportunities are off the chart.
Getting jobs for coders is probably one of the easiest thing if you're a coder, if you know how to
develop it is one of the most highly sought after opportunities.
But not only that, if you're the sort of person says, you know, I don't want that 8 to 6 p.m. job,
I want to be self-employed.
There is no other industry where you've got more opportunities to be self-employed than as a programmer.
You can be sitting on the desert island or in the coffee shop, writing code, selling apps, coding
for people.
Everyone is looking for someone to write code for them to write a program to help them.
Massive opportunities.
So those are them.
So easy to remember.
Why do you want to code fame its first fun achievement, these millennial age skills and earnings.
So that's why we want you on this course to enjoy everything.
And you're going to have a fantastic time.
And besides the fame, you're going to have a wonderful time.
See you on the other side.